it's a great pleasure to meet you sir
I've seen your videos a couple of times
on Facebook I didn't actually connect
the name to the face but I've seen you
have seen you a couple of times you've
been doing this for quite a while you're
an old you're an old warrior at this
that's right and we can talk about that
chewy stone is actually a few things I
want to ask you but my experiences and
my preference is that the conversation
just kind of takes on a life of its own
as we go and you know if we get stuck
somewhere I've got some questions
written down that I can fall back on but
otherwise if it's okay with you will
then spread let things go yeah I really
coordinate yeah you're recording now
yeah yeah yeah and what I normally do is
I put out a full version of it so
however long we talk for I put out a
full unedited version of it unless
there's anything you don't want to go
out there in which case I'll grab that
out but yeah feel free to say anything
you want and you have my assurance that
nothing will go on on line that you'll
not happy with you know what it means to
feel free to speak freely
that's her no so you were asking me I've
been at this for a long time well I
haven't had a huge amount of times
prepared for this because we only
decided a few days we were going to do
this right so a few of your videos but I
don't actually know anything about you
the man and so yeah start there give me
a sort of brief history in particular
with reference to your journey towards
becoming an RBE advocate if you if you
know yeah yeah yeah well you know I was
a musician for three or four decades you
know playing music in bars around here
and screaming into the mic midnight at
all and that's why my voice I don't
quite have the voice I used to sometimes
it sounds pretty horse but yeah I played
music for a long time then I got into
some video production writing
screenplays you know I sold the
screenplay 15 20 years ago and anything
I'm probably not it was on HBO and
Cinemax for a year or two there it's
called blood relations kind of a horror
thriller sense of humor
anyway go on it's not this either I've
seen it
yeah and then in there everyone that I
could shoot myself when TV do came out
and I lived near Aspen in Colorado about
a half-hour I built a house here about
40 years ago now so I had a bunch of
friends at work announcement at a dinner
theater and I got them to play the parts
in this movie just a little relationship
movie and shot it and that's on my DV
movie channel
that's called twisted faith and that's
where I did that you know I learned how
to do some video editing and then I
stumbled on site guys addendum around
two thousand eight or nine so that's ten
years ago and when he saw the addendum
was it like was it like a sudden
cataclysmic shift in your thinking or
was it like a seed that grew or how did
it work for you you know it was pretty
much cataclysmic I just saw you know how
the world worked
yeah I kind of knew a little bit about
the Baker's I didn't really understand
the fractional reserve lending Ponzi
scheme that they're controlling us with
and once you learn that it's hard you
it's hard to stay still anymore once you
really know how we're being controlled
by the bankers and then you know the
John Perkins thing with our foreign
policy that we get and you can see that
now of those every country really we're
just going around stealing their
resources and and then of course the
resource-based economy at the end of
that yeah I was pretty much hooked into
it and then was moving forward that was
about the time 2011 I think I started
making videos and you know Peter Joseph
described this stuff and you know he's
got a great voice and it describes it
fairly simply but sometimes it's a
little too more too intellectual maybe
lecture sounding and so I just thought
well I wonder if there's a way I can you
know get this information across in a
friendlier or a more accessible manner
for Pia and bull bite sizes right yeah
because I mean it tends to be an hour or
more
and even you know even for me I find it
a little bit and I'm into it right yeah
so I strongly mention addendum because
it was the addendum was was the one for
me as well and something that occurred
to me as you were talking though if I if
I if you don't mind just ask you when
when you sort of connected the dots with
the central banking scheme and the
tendrils extending through the
commercial banking system and into the
mortgage market and wreaths you know
lending money back to gut lending grab
government's own currencies back to them
at interest and all and all of this kind
of thing and did you see straight away
this being a intentional mechanism by
which the labor and creativity was being
sucked out for the vast majority of
people or was it like no one really knew
because I mean I it seems to me that the
internet and I think I've seen you make
this point in one of your videos that
until twenty years or so ago nobody knew
about this right there's a it's still a
fairly small percentage but there are a
growing number of people actually get it
as a mechanism of slavery as opposed to
oh yeah well bankers create money out of
man cuz I get lots of people that
understand you base create money out of
nothing but I don't get that they
understand the implications of that and
the unpayable that just builds up and up
and up and up and up you know what I
mean I think in two thousand one hundred
and sixty trillion dollars of debt and
sixty trillion dollars of money you know
in dollars of unpaid up out there you
know what I mean you'll understand the
ramifications of this what's your take
on that
yeah I understood it fairly quickly once
I saw it laid out there of how really
it's just a system to control people to
put people into debt that they can you
know never pay off her you know
sometimes you may be lucky enough to pay
it off but mostly it's just continually
creating more debt and you have to
borrow more to to stay in the game and
they are just sucking the money out of
people and controlling us like slaves
and it didn't take long to see that
so yeah that's how do you find that
people are refres the people that have
sort of it's been exposed to the idea of
the central banking fraud do you think
that they appreciate the the the depth
and the complexity of it for the most
part I mean either broadly speaking it
did you if I try to explain it to people
you know a lot of times their eyes kind
of glaze over after me they don't they
don't really want to look into it or
think about it too hard so some people
will kind of understand it a lot of
people is just well this is just the way
it is
yeah okay you can't really do anything
about it the reality of this love their
slavery in the face right I mean that's
a hard place yeah yeah you know that's
been a main motivator for me especially
then you know I built a house here and
I've had to borrow against it and again
a few times just to keep my head above
and just think of how these bankers are
just making up the money I don't know
where you want us to pay him back with
interest which is never created she
doesn't exist
and if you can't do it they get your
house they get your car whatever they're
loaning your life the game physical
chairs with fewer and fewer chairs in
the game constantly if you don't a few
chairs yeah yeah absolutely and then you
know I Rebecca in sort of studied at the
beginning of this country here when the
founders were trying to escape from the
control of Britain and and you know we
were told well you know the revolution
it was really just about their
government you know that mean government
over there charging its taxes and well
actually it was the bankers who owned
the government who were willing to you
know to get us into their fractional
reserve system and that was the real
thing you know Benjamin Franklin when he
was back he was in France a couple
decades before the Revolution and the
colonies were doing great
and people were asking about this
newfound prosperity in the colonies how
are you doing it and he said in the
colonies we create our own currency we
make our own money and we made just
enough to society
have no interest to pay to anyone
and certainly after that the King George
and the bankers who really owned him
they said no we'll have none of that
you're gonna be on our money system
you're gonna pay US taxes in gold and
silver and he said within a year the
conditions had reversed so dramatically
from the prosperity that now there were
unemployed in the streets and you know
once you get in the system where they're
sucking the wealth out of it you know
and he said the refusal of King George
to allow the colonies to operate an
honest money system which freed the
ordinary man from the clutches of the
manipulators the king was probably the
prime cause of the revolution so we
never learned that in school that it was
the bankers and their fractional reserve
lending system that was probably the
real reason you know we do a it's just
missed names right because there's no
taxation without representation or that
was there that was the that was the
slogan right but what on earth acts
ation other than interest payments on
central bank loans to the government I
mean that's that's basically what so
it's kind of the same thing it's just
not called that and that's what our
taxis are going for now you know we're
you know we we got rid of the bankers
for a while they came back over the past
couple hundred years and then in 1913
they got in there with the Federal
Reserve's impact and they passed it on
Christmas Eve right we thought soon all
sentences in the house and since then
and then they set up the IRS you know it
was set up right after they installed
the coal reserve that's basically their
collection agency to collect their
interest and so you know just to see all
this interest made the taxes that were
paying now most of it is going to the
central bankers and the rest I think for
bonds and military that's where our
taxes go so
it's such a horrible system we've got to
break free of it and that's the only way
I think we can truly break free is to do
what the founders wanted to do was get
rid of the central bankers and have our
own money system which was as fair as
you can possibly know yes that money is
created in order to serve a purpose and
they must the purpose of serving the
money is pay back it is destroyed and
it's removed from circulation and it
stays in balance as a consequence of the
amount of money's in circulation the
amount of money owed are always equal to
each other right right it's interesting
how few people understand the notion
that when a loan is paid back the money
that pays back that loan is destroyed I
find it interesting how few people
understand that notion give that the
money was created out for loan in the
first place
it must annihilate when it comes back
into contact right I matter/antimatter
thing but again I find it interesting
how few people appreciate that notion
out there there's a terrible lack of
education about the realities of
economics in our society deliberately so
they're obvious reasons right but it's a
real shocking lack yeah so if you don't
mind sorry I just about to say something
though I didn't want to interrupt you
I was just probably gonna call out about
the bankers you have been and are going
to be in next year a presidential
candidate I mean I so political process
and about what it's like being a being a
candidate yeah yeah I mean let's let's
start with the first thing I mean I'm
just curious about a few things if you
don't mind in terms of how it works over
there I'm obviously English and so
during your candidacy do do you have a
right to be on the debates with you know
the Republican and Democrat and whatever
candidates do you have that right oh no
oh this stuff is really sad in this
country I think we're probably more
controlled than any other country when
it comes to elections because they have
got the two-party system
and so they've got the you know the big
democratic debates coming up they've got
24 people running but they're cutting
that down to 20 they're having two
nights of ten each and that's coming up
soon to start yet we're a year and a
half away from the election which is
another thing that's crazy it's just a
distraction the electoral cycle yeah
yeah yeah it should be you know three or
four months we should just start it and
then finish it but no it's a great
distraction for them and so yeah we've
got and then there's Green Party for the
third a third party and there's the
libertarians for a fourth party and
they've been very serious about getting
their party registered in all 50 states
right every every state has different
requirements for that so you may need to
go out and get seven thousand signatures
on the petition and then submit that to
the state and then have meetings and a
charter and so it's a lot of Hoops that
you have to drunk jump through just to
be able to get your party registered and
get a candidate on the ballot some
states have different requirements for a
minor party where you don't need quite
as much and then there's always you
could run as an independent which which
I will probably end up doing because you
know if we had thousands of people in
this country backing well we're trying
to do with the money free from party we
could we could get on the on the ballots
as money through party is a minor party
but you know there's not a lot of people
jumping in line to get out and work at
this because it really does seem so
hopeless they ask you because you've
looked at the last elections where the
Democrats and the Republicans get about
95 percent of the votes and the other 5%
is split up between the Green for
negative to purse and libertarians 2%
compared to 45 to 50% for the Republic
and everybody feels like they're just
throwing their vote away if they vote
for a third party and this year it's
going to be worse than
never because you know everybody just
wants to get Trump out of there except
for his supporters so there's going to
be thirty thirty five percent of his
supporters and then everybody else is
just going to be going through the
Democrat even if it's another corporate
Democrat like Biden if we had Bernie in
there tulsi gabbard who's against the
wars if we had those those people in
there I'd be a little more excited but I
don't think the Democratic establishment
will even let that happen so as he said
in one of your videos I mean I've heard
you say exactly this that you know even
if you get genuinely well-intentioned
people elected they are still stuck with
this apparatus with the inertia built
into the apparatus is overwhelming you
know and however so it is the apparatus
that needs to change and I mean this is
this is one of the leading naturally -
it's one of the angles I wanted to
explore with you was the possibility of
is there any kind of possibility of
institutional driven change ie top-down
change driving us towards RBA or some
kind of more sustainable system is is
that even possible I mean I understand
that your campaign is primarily a
platform from which to speak you're not
actually hoping to implement any
policies right is it's a publicist it's
a way of gaining more notoriety in
publicity primarily right yeah it's
educational than just to get to present
this new economic system or presidential
candidate lends you a certain amount of
credibility right I mean people are also
actually gonna listen to you a little
bit more because you're a presidential
candidate that's right and I get that
from Richmond Ausmus to a few a few four
years ago whenever he started running I
found out about that that I you know got
to know him and saw that he was getting
out there and talking to people and yeah
what a great way to get this message
across to people and everybody in these
know many movements don't want to have
anything to do with politics you know
they say no we can't do we gotta move
beyond politics but while we're stuck in
this system you might say everything is
politics really at this point so you
know here was a chance to really just
get heard by more people and so that's
why I started
20:16 i made the videos but it was not
really serious at all it was just trying
to lay out the train of thought though
they were very good I mean I almost all
of them I watched four or five of them
but they're there they're very very good
particularly the second one where you
really outline the problems what's the
slogan that you use bad for people that
that whole whole angle was excellent I
thought yes god it works against us
that's right the system works against us
you know if we want to sell more
pesticides or you know that's good for
business it's horrible for people and
more pharmaceuticals more pills to take
that's horrible for people really as
it's turning out but it's good for
business so I'm going to go through ten
examples of that and there are many many
more you could think of without trying
too hard right now it's a really good
angle because it is you can't argue with
it you know what I mean it's undeniable
you really critical persuasion you
really can't argue with this stuff um
another thing which I cast I think you
said something along these lines but it
also links to something else I've become
very interested in recently the idea
that we are manipulated by these
structures to act against our own
self-interest right yeah and this is you
know this is obviously profoundly
destructive in the long term and and
there's a there's a guy called Daniel
Schmitt and Berger I think his name is
I've heard of him familiar he's
interested in sort of deconstructing the
gayi
sorry this may take a couple of minutes
just for me to unpack all of this but he
and his competitors they talk about game
a and that game a is what we currently
play right game a is the swill the
attempted solution to how can large
numbers of people live together without
killing each other collaborate
effectively on large projects you know
making life better for everyone and and
whatever twelve thousand years since the
Agricultural Revolution or there abouts
maybe even before that we've been
playing game a right but the game a can
no longer cope with the complexity the
variation in demands of society no it's
just become too much for game a the
institutions are no longer able to cope
and so we must playing game be
our own survival we need to start
playing game B and the question then
becomes what is game B right and so many
of the things that they talk about that
are features that are aspects of game B
are directly relevant to our B I mean
they they they make absence like they're
talking about our B am it is like that
so they talk non-rival risk
collaboration so groups of people coming
together simply to in a spirit of
openness and honesty and vulnerability
right willing to be wrong really willing
to be stupid you know what I mean but
just this just popped into my head let
me say it let me put it out there see if
you guys if it means anything to anyone
else you know what I mean but this open
spirited collaboration can create an
emergent thing which is way more than
the sum of its parts and even more than
the sum of the parts and the
relationship between the parts you know
what I mean is this is this other thing
but this can only be done in a spirit of
non-rival nerds brought that non-rival
nurse nurse whatever you know what I
mean yeah honesty truthfulness
compassion the ability to really listen
to put your own ideology and agenda to
one side you know all of this kind of
stuff and that we as a society at the
moment are completely incapable of doing
that but we must learn because that and
and and that's all RPE right I mean
that's that's right at the heart of what
RB is actually all about yeah it's
moving to a collaborative society where
we can work together and we can produce
abundance and such a wonderful trusting
society if we move the collaboration but
when we are forced to stick in this
system work we're forced to fight each
other that's what this is you know it's
cutthroat competition sorry we are
forced to fight each other to gain
advantage over each other and it doesn't
allow us to have any trust you when it
comes to business you can't trust
anybody everybody is trying to get the
best of the deal and it's it's really a
system that goes against our true nature
you know it's a system that produces
selfishness and greed
and that's why people say well this is
human nature just look at us but no this
is human behavior that's one point
absolutely behavior then results from
the system in which we're living and you
know studies on the brain and they can
tell when we are able to collaborate
when we can express our empathy and our
compassion and you know to want to feel
part of the community and be loved this
is really our true human nature this is
what makes people healthy and so you
know this is simply what we have to do
is move out of this competitive system
move into a collaborative system where
we're allowed to work together and
create an abundance and this is the only
way out of this this dilemma that we're
stuck in this suicidal ecocidal system
that it's just killing us you know but
we've been running what what these guys
would refer to as game a code but this
rival risks chipping off each other you
know in order for me to win you have to
lose
you know fear of scarcity in the future
prompt me to hoard and be greedy you
know way way beyond what is actually
reasonable do you think it's reasonable
to expect people to uninstall game a
code order you know whatever you want to
call it and you know it's it's a hell of
a leap well it is when you're that side
of it it's funny I was talking to
Richard about this when you get to the
other side of it and you look I think
all that was really easy that's change
perspective but when you're on the other
side of it it's you know should be not
you know what I mean it's it's I
actually think it's going to be easy for
people to transition into this society
when they see the benefit if they could
only have it laid out in front of them
and explained look we can actually be
working together and produce an
abundance of the things we need
localized all
as much as production as we need we can
go to a 20 hour work week that's all we
would have to do you know we know it
would get rid of war and it would get
rid of taxes and you know so many things
that everybody right now is it's killing
us and you know I know people are very
Washington to thinking well this is the
only way it is but if they could just
have a look at how it could be and just
understand that and see it I mean it
would be good to be able to see this
somehow you know rather than some just
trying to explain it to somebody but you
know that's why I don't think this
project is in the process of raising
funds to design and build a trial City
right I mean that would that would be
nice that would be nice yeah too late
they should have done this 50 years ago
but the road and we could actually you
know be be moving in like this now yeah
I forgot I'm gonna say there I'm sorry
for interrupting no you know what can we
take a break during the weekend
absolutely
I like your chair once he got up I
realized you'll share with a couple of
pandas I like your chair yeah like if
they're always a blank is not at the
upholstery as a blanket over it right
okay yeah yeah say is um when I want to
talk about this new system to people
rather than going right to the point of
money free or no money moving through a
moneyless society or scarcity you know I
don't do that so much now I just say
that'll be a step once we can produce an
abundance of the things we need we can
make it three but we're gonna have to do
that maybe step by step over that when
I'm talking about money free party I'm
meaning free freedom from the bankers
free freeing ourselves from the bankers
in the corporate state that's where we
need to get had need a lot of people
have been talking about this modern
monetary theory and
he have you heard about em yeah well you
know it's just the truth about how our
money is is this positive money those
kinds of guys is it that is it that kind
of free currency basically as is yeah
you know I'm not sure about so much of
exactly how it works that they're still
going to be some debt but you know the
money that is that's made up for a
military budget when suddenly we want
400 billion more dollars we need money
to bail out the two or three trillion
dollars to be bail out the bankers after
2008 it's not like they taxed us and we
had to pay taxes to come up with that
money
they just created you they just created
out of thin air and here's two trillion
dollars for the bankers goes on their
own are dead but you know nobody's
taking the dentist no let's do that to
properly finance schools or healthcare
or road building or you know what I mean
II projects or energy transfer projects
or whatever when they get around to
anything that's gonna help your
education or then they go we're gonna
have to raise taxes we're gonna have to
take it out of the budget in reality we
can just make that money up too and so
that's the basic theory but ya know I
have read something about that I have
read something and it doesn't it can be
interest-free and so they're actually
way of destroying money right they take
money in a day they tax people in order
to remove money from circulation so the
money has brought into circulation out
of nothing and then they're done to take
money out of circulation that's that
basic idea isn't it yeah yes and so we
can make up whatever may we need we can
move it from this top-down system of
bankers on top we can start at the
community level and be making up as much
just like Benjamin Franklin said in
those times back then he said
we've created some of currency to
facilitate trade and industry and make
sure everyone has their basic needs met
we can make enough money to do that so
so moving money free it's moving away
from the banking system and we can keep
a monetary system as we go about trying
to produce an abundance of one product
and then the next because you know I you
don't ask people to believe you what do
you say oh we can free to produce an
abundance of things and we don't need to
charge for it they're gonna go really
well I'm not sure about that
well fine let's not ask all that in the
beginning let's just say let's work at
producing abundance with very little
human labor involved and you know people
working 10 hours re contributing to
these projects when we can make enough
you know using automation we can just
take away the price tag one product
after another and you know within if we
switched into a system like this within
a year or two if we localizing food food
would be three ninety ninety percent of
it we've already could be we're already
producing enough food for everyone on
the planet which is 40 percent of it
right I mean we're already working that
there's already no but essentially in
abundance you know doing all intensive
press you know this is a really secure
you'll probably already know this but
the reason that we don't give our
surplus food away so starving countries
in the third world is this is lower the
market price of food and therefore it
can't be done just unbelievably nuts go
okay you carry on because something you
were saying just so you carry on I just
want to turn you to make that point of
what I'm trying to push with this these
policies here in my presidential
campaign is not be free of money
immediately but yeah just moving off
immediately moving off the bankers
immediately dissolving the banks and the
corporations
and and then getting rid of this
hierarchy this pyramid with the
government and the president the
Congress and the lawmakers in the courts
trickling down to the people at the
bottom we have to flip that over we have
to give control to the communities yes
lots of little hierarchies community the
community hierarchies lots and lots of
little ones back on top of each other as
larger Brockett projects need to be
undertaken wider range of collaboration
you can stack these little things on top
of each other absolutely right and then
it can focus down in the pyramid - we
have a a resource management team I was
calling it in 2016 and now I'm saying we
could call it a council we can have a
council of elders or a Council of
experts that we nominate because I don't
know if you saw in my campaign or on my
website I'm when I'm talking about it so
let's you not a president electing a new
socio-economic system for president a
system that does not need a president
and you know when you talk to the
anarchists or other words they don't
want a president and there's a lot
there's a lot of reasons that makes a
lot of sense to not have you know our
supreme leader our king or our president
and instead nominate people in the
different fields no heavy Department of
Earth Sciences and clean water and
Atmospheric Sciences and get people who
are experts like a dozen people a
Department of Peace Andrey nominate
people to do that and they don't have to
do it for long just too much for a year
there's a lot of you know until the
project is done and then the institution
is dissolved because the projects done
right institutions don't need to last
forever they need to last for as long as
they're useful and then they can be
dissolved and we move on you know I mean
fluid fluid yeah so yeah yeah
I think a key point as well just going
back to what you were saying they you
would you would also be by changing the
focus of society so dissolving the
corporation's the banks they're the
government's and refocusing so
on the creation of abundance of
everything that we can think of right
there that shit focus all of a sudden
because Richard made this point I think
he's absolutely right the people that
many of the people that enter these
professions accountancy finance the law
these are the best and brightest of us
right these are hardworking ambitious we
have an intelligent individuals right we
will be well advised to harness those
energies for the furtherance of the
species rifle event and the better and
the best moment of everybody's lives and
Britain's great strengths Rhys he
doesn't see how his enemies he wants to
bring them in every benefit everybody
and you would be freeing them for all
the people working in the financial
industry something useful they probably
have interests in this other stuff they
wanted to do and they're trapped in this
like you and so is everyone who works in
the insurance agency there's another
industry that actually produces nothing
just like the financial sector actually
produces nothing everyone who works in
accounting and advertising marketing the
IRS all these people are just pushing
numbers around on paper we want to free
all these people to let them come back
and just work in their communities in
their homes around you know closeby they
just have community projects going on
and these people who are pretty smart
they can get in there and help be the
leaders in these projects but that's
what we were free everybody from working
in jobs that produce nothing and that's
how you can justify going to a 20 hour
work week because we have twice as many
people now you know we I'd say to people
you know if we if we had everyone who
worked at food production in any area of
that housing construction transportation
health care all these things we need if
they stopped going to work for a week or
two I mean everything would just small
if it's everyone who works in the
financial or a more highly automated
right but for right now they work how
they work and people need to keep doing
what they're doing for right now this
minute yeah yeah absolutely
then you do then you take everybody who
works in the financial sector insurance
install tomorrow yeah if they didn't go
to work as a favor you're not a damn
thing would change we could just keep
moving on well not only would nothing
not only would nothing change but
actually things would get better because
they wouldn't be scalping office anymore
they wouldn't be today they wouldn't be
taking their cut office anymore
that's right things would be getting so
much better that's it free free everyone
let's not look at it we're taking away
their job we're setting you free now
that actually have an opportunity to do
something you wanted you help with your
communities it's gonna be much more
intrinsically valuable to you to you and
everyone mental health issues go down
corn goes down I mean all of this anyway
we're treading the same way it's reading
the same old ground aren't we there was
something that came to my attention just
talking about going back a little bit
talking about political processes
there's something that came to my
attention a little while ago as a woman
she's part of a larger movement I can't
remember her first name or cassio Cortez
who was elected to be Congress she will
be a Democratic Alliance is it you know
she's probably party but when she and
Bernie Sanders its democratic socialism
right is what they're sort of pushing
Alliance I'm not sure you know the
Republicans have the Tea Party and the
Democrats have this and I think it's
called the Democratic Alliance but I
could be wrong about that I'm not
certain of the main khajur yeah my the
the question I wanted to ask you with a
point I want to make about this was that
from what I understand and listen I've
only seen a few reports about it from
what I understand this is a real
grassroots movement and their support
came from not raising lots and lots of
money and buying lots and lots of TV
time and sending around lots of leaflets
but by recruiting lots of people to go
and knock on doors and actually talk to
people and you know
town hall meetings and this kind of
thing and build support by actually
interfacing with the people that are
going to be voting for you
and I I wonder if there is some
relationship possibly to be formed
because I think in many ways you or the
RBE movement and and they are very much
on the same page in a lot of ways I mean
I know they still have to see the the
necessity to get rid of the money market
but but nevertheless there's potential
alliance to be made there what do you
think you know it's just really still
stuck within our two-party system and
the Democrats and they can they will
never talk about the central bankers
getting rid of the Fed will never talk
about the corporate state controlling
every branch of government now and if
they get elected like you were saying
that the structure is still in place
which is going to prevent them from
really coming up with much change
they'll be small little changes little
band-aids we put on the system but
nothing is going to really change that
much no I I don't really I can't see
anything great happening with a Democrat
being elected the only thing I think we
need to do is the only thing we can do
to get out of this system as I said
dissolve the banking institutions and
dissolve the corporations and this is
also you know I don't talk about how the
founders wanted to get rid of the
bankers they also did not trust
corporations they would give them never
give them a charter to for some project
build a road or canals when that was
finished they were dissolved they didn't
want corporation so you know me or us
calling for an end to the bankers and
the corporate state that shouldn't be
too radical when people understand
that's what the founders of this country
actually wanted but it really is to most
people right listen I completely agree
with you eyelets and we're absolutely on
the same page of course we are those
you know right but you know how how does
that come about how you know where does
the authority to dissolve because that's
a pretty it's a pretty dramatic change
right over to the structure of society
where to authority to make that decision
and take action come on okay so we can't
really have any change and dramatic like
that as long as we're working under this
constitution that's the Constitution is
the playbook that's the rules of the
game and you know people in this country
that we love our Constitution it's
sacrosanct you know and you can't change
that but they really probably haven't
read it you know whatever 27 amendments
or something so there was no bill of
rights in the beginning you know the
system set up by the when they said all
men are created equal in our
Constitution what they really meant was
all wealthy landowning white men are
created equal it actually says does it
no I believe it actually says one white
man is worth two or two-thirds of
two-thirds of black man or something
like that it's actually written down in
there isn't there right when they wrote
the Constitution it was to set up this
structure that they have now with the
hierarchy to make sure nothing could
check nothing much could change that it
could keep going on for them and then
enough people said wait a minute you
know you know there's nothing in there
to protect individual freedoms and so we
need something we'll call the Bill of
Rights and this came about three years
after the Constitution enough people
finally got in there know we're gonna
have freedom of the press freedom of
speech freedom to assemble to petition
your government there's like 10 things
in the Bill of Rights which became the
first 10 amendments to the Constitution
so many people say over though the
Constitution they're really saying we
love the Bill of Rights those things are
later the rest of it assists the
structure in the government and you know
that is to where it's just this
hierarchy in control that makes sure
nothing's going to change and so if we
want the kind of change we're talking
about we have to rewrite the
Constitution we have to have an update
we update everything else we have an
updated this document in 240 years it
desperately needs an update they had a
whole while back about the approval
rating for Congress
92% only 8% approval ratings 92% of the
people said you know this Congress had
doesn't work it is broken
it is dysfunctional and that's the
Constitution that's the part we need to
update certainly any amendments to the
Constitution as I could be wrong about
that it's something like this needs to
be passed by two-thirds majority in the
house right and compare the ones that
need to actually change the Constitution
and they're the ones that ain't gonna
because that's what that's what puts
them there right that's why we had to
tear the new constitution back then
again I come back to my question before
where does the authority come to create
and impose that new constitution I mean
what you're what you seem to be alluding
to is revolution that's what I mean
that's basically what you're talking
about right is some form of popular
revolution where we say we over we
basically overthrow the gun whether
violently or not but basically we
overthrow the government in some way and
we install a new set of rules a new
constitution that's what you're talking
about yeah yeah a new manual like Bucky
fuller you know but mr. fuller is like
Jacque fresco and arthur c clarke
science you know what if we let science
take the lead here instead of having a
society run a country run by bankers
corporations military why not scientists
and engineers futurists technisches like
these people and but Mr Fuller said oh I
forgot exactly what I was talking about
it you know his thing was the
old game let's change the game and yeah
he in a1 Wallach sentence his world game
said make the world work for 100% of
humanity in the shortest possible time
through spontaneous cooperation without
ecological damage or disadvantage to
anyone so did he call it the manual for
spaceship earth he coined that term
spaceship earth we are all one people on
this spaceship earth and we need a new
we need to make a manual that works for
that and we can call it a constitution
but anyway so what we want to do is have
a constitutional convention come up with
another constitution that will allow us
to put together this society as we see
it this new model new model of a social
system economic system so at the end of
the year you know we're gonna be talking
about this through the months ahead and
then have people put in ideas let's put
up a new a new constitution if we want
to change we're gonna have to have we
can't do it within the system we can't
do it with this constitution and so
there'll be a system that doesn't need a
president that's gonna have a Council of
experts and then in the musclehead next
its 2020 will be nominating people to be
to lead in the different departments and
maybe a dozen or so and so we're ready
for the election
we're not electing a president we're
electing a new council a new playbook or
Constitution oh you know just a whole
new system and it's ready to go
it'll have it all laid out it's not me
that's gonna be President you know I get
if I win I get to go home and work in my
garden and help it he'll help in my
community 20 hours a week or something
that's what everybody can do we'll have
a counselor and he's here are the people
we'll look at their background rather
have these people at the forefront of
decision-making rather than you know
I've been making this point for a long
time I mean in the UK I cannot remember
the last time that we had a teacher in
charge of the education department for
example you know these yeah people's
career politicians who went and studied
you know politics philosophy and Laura
Oxford whatever you know got it up
politics got a seat in the House of
Commons and now they're running the
education where the fuck is your
qualification where is your experience
where why should you be doing this job
you know what it involves are you
talking about our in our Department of
Education on it in the UK but I'm sure
ours is just as ridiculous because it's
broke appointed this Betsy DeVos a woman
who you know married into the Amway
portion and has given six hundred
million dollars over the past years to
the Republicans has never worked a job
in her life never went to public schools
he nominated her as their Secretary of
Education and so that's it's just as
ridiculous neil degrasse tyson the
scientist you know he was on Joe Rogan
talking about when are we gonna see
scientists in our Congress you know it's
something the lawyers yeah business
businessman we need scientists in there
so sometimes I want to call the money
free party the science party because I
think money frees I've said this before
so a couple of people I think money free
sends people down the wrong line of
thinking you know what I mean there's
too much at the beginning money free you
know what I mean it's too big it's too
big and big first as you've done I think
the the sequence you followed in your
campaign videos I think was excellent he
started at the beginning these are the
problems these why the problems happen
this is the real root of the problem and
here is what the world could look like
if we did it like this and this and this
instead you know I mean you follow in my
opinion followed exactly the right sort
of sequence of progress
all right he's talking about my videos
there I was thinking when we were
talking in the beginning how did I get
into this and I was talking I wanted to
simplify the message that Peter Joseph
was pretty got there and so I made
something called the resource-based
economy' game where I had a little game
board and I rolled the dice and I had
piles the WTF pile you know the problems
here and it pick a car car let me move
around and it would be you know the
question would be you know does the for
the bank's really they just went through
there were about twelve question to the
whole thing and each one was about 10
minutes the number by nine of them and
so it was about an hour and 45 minutes
when I got it finished and then I
shortened it down to 45 minutes and that
was the first thing that I did was this
resource-based economy game which was
way back in 2011 or 12 I believe and
it's kind of fun to watch I think and
maybe in the in the description of the
video you know we can put some links to
a couple of my videos that people have
probably never seen because they're
older but there are some good ones there
and I could do that I could send you
just the link guys the game or something
like that there is the title of it isn't
it I didn't actually watch those I spent
my time watching some of your other
stuff but I know what you're talking
about
yeah your most-watched video actually is
as far as I can tell anyway maybe I'm
wrong correct me if I'm wrong you almost
watch video with 43,000 views is the one
where you talk about the benefits of
hemp and there's something that I
thought we might because either I used
to talk down at speakers corner in
London I don't know if you know what
speaker's corner is but I used to go
down there have the occasional rent and
I got I got to meeting a guy down there
he lives on the streets he's an old guy
long beard dirty clothes that kind of
thing rides around on a
right with big panniers on it with all
of his shit in it and he had a thing
about him growing huge plate and then
using it as a construction material and
the hemp it's at the hemp also recycled
you know rejuvenates the soil and and
you know starts to reach stimulate the
the rejuvenation of the environment it's
a building material it's as you said a
poly you can use it to manufacture
polymers rope clothing you know what I
mean it's it's like a gift from God this
stuff plastics we could make health
based plastics rather than oil based
plastics presumably it's all
biodegradable and you know food it's the
best food the best vegetable on the
planet people don't think hemp or
cannabis is a vegetable but even the
psychoactive cannabis if you don't heat
it it doesn't become psycho magic so you
can eat raw camp which doesn't have much
si-hu or raw cannabis and it's better
than broccoli or all these other
vegetables and that's all the essential
amino I'm you know you can tell I start
to lose my voice here wow it's the best
food yeah so I made this video that's a
half hour and the first half of it goes
to all the benefits of all the products
like usually building materials fabrics
and clothes and then the second half is
the medicinal applications for it how it
actually can cure cancer it kills cancer
cells yeah
bolsters our immune system it's uh fixes
the communication between our brain and
our organs like when people are having
seizures too much information is getting
through you take the the CBD or and it
turns down like a faucet so not enough
gets through or if you know you you've
lost your appetite or you have been
chemo you have no appetite evil
open up those passageways and yeah it's
the most amazing gift from God nothing
nothing I believe phrase no same but
yeah you know to the human race and
these cannabinoids they're inside this
plant it turns out we discovered those
in the plant and then we discovered we
make the exact same chemical compounds
which renamed cannabinoids in us our
endo and dodges cannabinoid system and
even in mother's milk there's small
amounts of THC and CBD and these because
what they do is they regulate our body
functions and repair the body and sick
cells the cancer cells they kill all
those and it's the most amazing thing so
yeah I am
a huge health advocate and yeah that's a
really good video people really like
that one and then I made one called
money in the future a resource-based
economy which is 20 minutes where I just
go through the train of thought and you
know in the RBE and I've got little
segments in there clips
Captain Picard in which you've probably
seen that video where he's going you
know in the future there is no money
I quite like the Star Trek particularly
the next door excuse me I'm just
changing position I quite like Star Trek
particularly the next generation as a
pretty decent approximation of what the
RBA will lower would look like twenty
years down the road you know what I mean
III think it's not a bad ya sense
absolutely you know that's we want to
better ourselves we no longer compete
though we no longer compete for trinkets
we work to better ourselves you know
this guy says well what's what's the
go-to
learn you know to better yourself then
to enrich yourself yeah this is for me
this is the grand vision of RBE right is
that all the world becomes an
educational facility for every single
person that lives in it right every
single person is a teacher a learner a
supervisor a doer you know what I mean
everyone just just I don't know fit this
tapestry kind of thing is constantly
changing evolving chemistry yeah I'm
still I'm still I mean I I agree with
everything you say and I love the way
you say it as well your your your
passion is it cause through every single
word that you say and I'm a big admirer
of people like you and like Richard
who've been doing this for a long time
and if somehow managed to find an
antidote to the frustration of you know
banging on a brick wall
you know because and if anything things
are getting worse out there right we're
racing faster and faster and fiesel
towards that cliff edge it seems like
you know what I mean and I know efforts
have been in vain because you know which
is that doesn't seem to be changing it's
also I know politics is is one way to be
able to talk about this and get people
where you know when it's election season
and people are listening to new policies
people are putting out new ideas you
think it's a great way to get this
information out there but you know if if
not if you're just a person like the
millions of supporters that we have but
still a daily basis when we're so stuck
inside the system it's like what can I
do to maybe do this like if I want to
start a tool library well there's a guy
down in our town that hears it he has a
business we're here it's out tools so if
we start a Tool Library business yeah
yeah
business leaders family and yeah yeah
sure to take a step forward with this
when we're in a system
this just got us it's just holding us
back
so correct me if I'm wrong because I am
detecting a little bit of frustration in
you here because on the one hand you
agree the top-down institutional driven
chain not possibly happened right
because the institutions are the did the
other distillation of the very
structures that trying to overturn and
yet at the same time at a grassroots
individual small group level we are a
powerless and B sometimes doing more
harm than good by trying to by trying to
change at you know at a ground floor
level and so where does that you know
that that seems to me to be a bit of a
Mexican standoff whatever it is they
call it a chest yeah I know I know I
gave her sorry so I don't know about you
and not about me but I gave a talk
fairly recently at a zeitgeist
conference and this was kind of the
point that I was making is that the
individual does certainly feel like they
stand powerless against this diet via
mouth of a monster right yeah and so the
only thing you can do same time is doing
it enrich the meaningfulness of your own
life is to take it upon yourself to go
on what I conceptualize as Joseph
Campbell's hero's journey answer to
embark that hero's journey you know what
I mean see yourself as you know the
transformative agent in this world
confront your demons confront your dark
side you know what I mean wrestle
through those things acknowledge the
shadow that drives you the shadows that
drive society and and and create one
little tiny island of light in the
darkness right and then when you have
done that when you are if when you have
made yourself into a fit agent for
positive change in this world then that
will by its very nature radiate out to
others who do you know what I mean and
so yeah and I know it's slow and it's
agonizing
you think God you know it's one person
in eight billion and it's the only way I
see it maybe fantastical it may be you
know fairy tale but it is the only way I
see is at their individual
self-actualization kind of point you
know what I mean it yeah it's it's a
huge burden on the individual it's a
massive acts of responsibility you know
taking one of the big problems I kind of
this is another part of the Mexican
standoff is that on the one hand we have
no hope of institutional top-down
meaningful goods change taking place and
at the same time we have been very
thoroughly habituated to rely on
top-down institutional driven change to
make changes in society right it's the
only way for changes to come about is
that government makes a new law or
government start you know legislation
whatever so again this leads us to this
point where on the one hand we're
waiting for top-down shame on the other
hand top-down strange ain't never coming
yeah I know and it's frustrating for
everyone all of us in this movement you
know we get positive you have days where
you you know you just getting input into
it you see positive things that are
being shared stories out there and you
feel we're making our way long and we
are weird people are getting more
educated that we're making our way along
and you know then the movements come
along and occupy and extinction we've
got all these things are coming along
and I just see him as another straw on
the back and at some point it's gonna
break and so when you're occupy kind of
came and went that's okay I guess that's
just a natural way that that was going
to happen but it was a big straw that
led to the night consciousness occupy it
may not have led to anything concrete
immediate but it definitely changed the
constant I mean it inculcated the
concept of the 99% didn't it I mean
that's that's where I'm not saying they
originated that idea but that's what
brought it into sort of broad awareness
that calm you know you know it's getting
to a point where just changing one by
one slowly we could get there in 50
years but we don't really have no with
the environment I've listened to
Christian hedgers talk a lot of you
listen to Chris yeah yeah he's a
wonderful an amazing person and then
create activist and writer and you know
he more than anybody he sees the reality
of what's happening with our environment
and he has kids and he's afraid that
they're not going to have much of a
world I have a couple of boys in their
20s and I'm kind of maybe if I didn't
have kids maybe I wouldn't be doing it
so much I probably would but that's one
thing that pushes in the armor to make
change so the next generation can have a
better life in Chris I just says you
know at this point the court the
corporate control has gotten to a point
where they control every lever of power
they have taken over every batch of
government and the only way we are going
to be able to turn this around he says
we just have to overthrow the
corporation's and most of the we but we
are the corporation's the people that
work doing this in the corporation the
workers they are the real corporate not
these people at the top they don't do
anything but they make some decisions
it's not stock and whatever no the
people are the corporation's so we can
get rid of the the name corporation and
the structure as it is now but just let
people continue with the same work but
the people make the decisions you know
just get rid of this word new corporate
and he says we have to overthrow the
corporation's and sound you know a
revolution it's scary to people that's
my transition a peaceful transition is
better and with overthrow the
corporation's I like dissolve which I'm
sorry doesn't have to it doesn't have to
be violent
right we can dissolve the corporations
and keep the same structures in place
what another way of saying get rid of
corporations be to say get rid of the
profit motive within the doing of
Commerce yeah the profit mode has to go
3d what it's about right I mean the
issue is is that is the need to make
primarily short-term profits at any cost
because now the next course is balance
sheet is what's going to determine my
bonus this year you know it's that it's
that kind of thinking that's when we
move from a competitive economic system
to a collaborative one the profit motive
is gone we the profit motive has to go
to corporate structure the bankers or we
can make money a local level just to
keep everybody going to make sure
everybody has their basic needs met and
to facilitate trade we keep money going
for that but you know the profit motive
has to go and in a collaborative society
there yeah there is no profit motive and
so that has to be the big change we have
to move from competitive to
collaborative from corporate control to
community control everything has to be
at a community level not too top-down
anymore we control our own money system
as long as we're going to need one so we
can produce enough abundance we can get
rid of it so we move from bankers to
community money from corporations to
community control from competition to of
collaboration and from 40 hours we extol
property to open sourcing and everything
and so yeah absolutely
my I keep coming back to where does the
pressure for these changes to occur come
from and put this correct me if I'm
putting words into your mouth but I are
you basically saying that it's a process
of Education and the when sufficient
number of people are educated then this
rejection of corporation and government
and central banking will come about on
its own is that is that base
sickly where you're coming from I'm I'm
saying within this political structure
we can we can vote in a new system
that's why I have on my I don't know if
you saw my website sailor 2020 yes I did
yes yes I went there I had a look at the
policy in 16 I did not put up a website
yeah it was just very loosely just
symbolic campaign sort of but this time
I put together a nice website and I
don't know if you've seen it but it's
okay yeah sailor 2020 dot-com and if
anybody listening to this I'm sure
they'll be the alinker that's human in
the description sailor like Taylor with
an s saya lor 2020 calm and on that
website it says at the beginning let's
elect a new socio-economic system let's
give science a shot let's put science at
the forefront of decision-making and
look at let's get rid of all debt that's
the number one thing we're going to do a
debt Jubilee now in this country that's
you know we have student debt which is
that one and a half trillion dollars
which is just so unconscionable that
we're giving this money to bankers and
putting our young people in debt prison
right off the bat so there's some talk
about oh we can forgive some student
debt no we're gonna forgive all debt
your home's your personal loans student
debt a debt you believe it's nothing new
it's been done throughout history you
can find it in the holy books maybe you
know what it would get too much they
were just wiping off the debt but we're
not going to start over with the same
name or we'll go like that's where
reverse we're having a dent you believe
and then we'll start over with a
collaborative system so if this sounds
good to you getting rid of all debt
working a 20-hour week taking care of
our planet if we have sign
and scientists futurists in the
forefront war is not gonna be an option
scientist Carl Sagan people like this
you're gonna think you know this big
Jacque fresco let's go to war
no war is not even an option in this new
system
so anyway I'm laying out a few things
here which is the policies the platform
of this let's vote in a new system
that's gonna have a the Council of
experts that will nominate there won't
have a president and all the everything
getting rid of yet having a dead you
believe working a 20-hour work week most
people would be willing to get behind
that absolutely yeah yeah this freedom
were all slaves
so let's free us from the bank I think
the charge that would get leveled at you
certainly by the establishment is that
you're unrealistic you know what I mean
this is a utopian vision you know it's a
childlike fantasy you know there's you
know there I'm sure you've heard it all
a million times but this is what gets
levelled at you and unfortunately
because they do control still a huge
amount of the megaphone that people
listen to this is this is in the minds
of many many many good but conventional
and not really that you know people this
is not guitars are you're a crackpot
right here you're a nutcase back yeah
but more and more of here people are not
trusting the news chill as we often you
know so people are getting away from
that and so yeah the people at the top
they're gonna try to say this is fantasy
I don't know chaos is gonna be horrible
but but you put these questions in front
of people you want to continue on in
debt or you will free yourselves from
dead you want stop all these wars stop
sending our kids off to Wars yes from
the fighting of them and then from the
reconstruction of the country afterwards
I need you but it's
such an outrageously monstrous message
scam you know anything on billions and
billions and billions of people for
centuries it's it's it's hard not to
laugh because it's so enormous it's so
deeply terrifying and depressing the
only really appropriate response is
laughter but the internet is saving us
on that too because before the internet
I know you know what I mean I know what
you mean but twenty years ago before
that when our government told us we had
to go to war and the whole constantly
got funded we thought now everybody is I
mean there's so many channels out there
talking about the real truth what's
going on as Venezuela
yeah and Syria and all these countries
so the internet is gonna be our Savior I
know it's been a downside also but it's
we wouldn't have a chance
without the internet in my opinion no I
completely agree with you I completely
agree
unfortunately there any problem is that
the internet the internet over the last
twenty years has been co-opted by the
very same structure that you know we
seek to alter I mean II to which
Facebook and Google and Instagram of
detail and control what people what
information people are exposed to what
goes on their newsfeed what their
recommendations are you know what they
get linked to all of all of us and of
stuff them to conform to the behavior
which the Internet is now expecting of
them it's terrifying well it really is
all this Huxley had AB something this is
we are very much entering braving the
world I mean I really I would I continue
to fight the good fight like you guys so
I can choose to fight the good fight but
I'm filled with an ever-increasing sense
of dread that we are heading down the
road of further totalitarianism and not
liberation and rbe I know especially was
a rose of the
you know the right and yeah from people
in countries all around the world you
know in Bolivia I mean enough Brazil
they've got a right we got it's just a
reaction to you know looking for an
outsider getting good something
something different something else
something else this is fine we'll have
that at least it's different or at least
it looks different yeah
so all these policies that I was talking
to you about you know would sound good
to so many people how do I get people to
hear me how do I get that message out
there and I don't vote for it I tell you
what came from have you ever seen
Brewster's Millions it's a fairly city
film with Richard Pryor's yes he has to
spend thirty billion dollars in 30 days
in order to get his inheritance of 300
million right but he's not allowed to
have any assets he got buy houses and
cars and shit like that he's not allowed
to have any assets at the end of it so
he strikes on the brilliant idea of
running a political campaign right and
if he loses he spent all this money on
the campaign he has no job at the end of
it and so he campaigns for none of the
above right don't vote for any of us
yeah and put a box on your plate but
none of the above and put the Box in
there now that is the kind of campaign
that I think because you're not you're
not appealing to any particular ideology
or set of values or set of policies or
anything like that just all we want is
hundreds of millions I mean what's the
electorate in the u.s. two hundred
million hundred fifty well it's it's a
hundred hundred million there's probably
two hundred fifty million eligible
voters we apparently get fifty percent
so it's a hundred million people if you
get twenty thirty forty million of those
people to vote none of the above I mean
this would only undermine in the eyes of
everybody the legitimacy of whatever
bunch of clowns are currently occupying
the positions of power that I did
because just for that for the first
neutrality right it's a it's a protest
though it's not about and I know the
problems of voting a making negative
stands I get there but it's actually a
positive stand because it's the
beginning of something new right it's a
rejection of this in order to make room
for the talking about something near
because at the moment there isn't even
the space to talk about it right it's
all red or blue right it's all cashed in
those terms there isn't even the space
Indian in India arena to talk about
anything else above to make that room
sorry I've repeated myself well you know
in 2016 I all they did was have my
social media Facebook basically friends
and that watched my videos and pass them
along to other people I may reach a
couple thousand people you know that's
it and this time it's just getting
started and this is the first interview
I've done and you know this is not going
to get too many views um but I mean
there's a guy named Jimmy door he's got
he's got a you know online alternative
news show which is great he's just great
and he's got a half a million
subscribers but one of the guys that's
on his show Graham Elwood has got his
own channel and he's got 20,000
subscribers and so I'm gonna be on his
show in the next week or two okay and
I'm hoping that will lead to possibly
get I getting on Jimmy doors so or that
this is what I have to do now I have to
try to make this a viable enough subject
for internet shows to want to have me on
to talk about the policies we're talking
about here and so I've got to kind of
hustle and do that and you know it's
pretty much me over here I mean you said
before that there's hundreds of
thousands or millions of supporters
around around the place and I don't deny
that in terms of their sentiments but in
terms of getting
they're talking to people rising staff
making writing music doing our blah blah
blah whatever it might be this is not
enough no we're nearing our yeah and so
that's what I'll you don't say on those
shows and that's what I'll say here at
the end of this show okay folks if
you're out there in this country anyway
you know go to the money free party USA
website and on there there's a page for
every where you click on your state and
from and then on there are there's a
thing you can fill in and say yeah I
would support this direction and I will
sign a petition to try to get you on the
get us on the ballot and so you know
anybody listening to this if you want to
do something to help this go to the
money free party USA website sign up
there spread this message my videos that
are out there my website is really good
just for people to quickly pull up and
see what this is all about so please
send along my website to anybody you
possibly can and other people around the
world you don't need to be a global
movement and we've got the money free
party in the UK in new zealand in
australia somebody's trying to get one
but not much I saw a Facebook page for
one in India but we need if you're
listening to this and you're in another
country start a money free party
Facebook page in your country how hard
is that it's not hard at all you know
and and you know and then you can see
how many liked you get post the kind of
topics we're talking about with your
money free party see how many people you
can get come aboard because I think if
we had the money free party going in
France yeah yeah you know I mean these
people really want change there and they
get out in protest or the viscosity in
France didn't they absolutely well this
very nicely it's one of the other things
I wanted to talk to you about was was
the fraction in fact you know what
before we get into this can do you mind
if I take a quick
oh yeah listen this happened with
Richard as well we ended up talking for
over two hours and I I chopped I chopped
the Edit down to about 15 minutes
I was actually the the video with
Richard was excellent I mean he's he's
been doing it a long time he really
knows what he's about he's got a really
good nature
I mean he's you know he sees he sees
people in a really positive light by
nature you know he's the ideal chap for
it and yeah he somehow manages to never
lose his never lose his enthusiasm for
it he actually thinks he genuinely
thinks I don't know whether he's deluded
or not I don't live his life so I can't
possibly say but he actually thinks that
RBE is a possibility in New Zealand like
soon in the next couple of years yeah
yeah and I'm gonna think that too just
because it makes me feel good you gotta
keep optimistic in this and and either
in this country we are the most
programmed brainwashed people in this
country on earth right off the bat I
think it's going to be another country
we may be a South American country
Bolivia they they want to the president
of Bolivia says we're getting off the
IMF and the World Bank we're getting out
of them you know said Rebecca once a
country can become pretty much
self-sufficient they can lead the way
but New Zealand I think is a really good
candidate for that too it's not that
many people there Jonathan I think
they're pretty forward-thinking and I
think they could see this thing through
and they could leave their way so I'm
I'm gonna side with Richard Woodall I
love to wake up when is it September
2020 I think was the date I mean I'd
love to wake up one morning and end here
on the news broadcast New Zealand has
adopted an entirely new and
revolutionary economic system yeah not
going to be doing oh they they're going
to be using money for a limited time but
they hope to phase it out in five years
or whatever it might be and in the
meantime they're gonna focus on
collaboration and the creation of
sustainable abundance for everybody
there with no bankers you know they're
just crack on and do it they're not
gonna wait for anyone
giving permission they're just gonna
crack on and do it that's yeah other
people just we can just keep doing what
we're doing together that's what I say
and in 2016 videos number seven was
whether it's called the plan the
transition and and in that one I said
it's just happening where we could just
you know pick a day we're gonna do this
and just start doing it without money
and people can just keep doing what
they're doing it are the jobs that are
important that are necessary and would
get rid of all the jobs you don't
produce anything but in the meantime
yeah those people that are doing the
necessary jobs can get some help right
they can get a little bit of assistance
for all the people that are not working
anymore
they can go to halftime so we can just
keep doing what we're doing but we
really have to get into localizing all
as much production as we can because you
know depending on corporations then to
produce it in one place and ship it
everywhere around the world you know
that's that's not a model that's gonna
work so if we're every community is
growing through around them and every
community is growing hemp in the fields
around them you're making clothes
building materials energy purifying
their own water absolutely yeah so we
just gotta focus on that you know we
could just keep doing what we're doing
and you know localization smashes the
power of the corporations and and this
is always where I get stuck you know I
mean III the the the vision is is clear
in my head the problems here are clear
in my head but the mechanism by which
you create the demand for the change
that's the only way it comes about right
is there is sufficient demand in the
population the thing that's the only way
it comes about and and the the mechanism
by which you go about generating that
demand remains unclear to me I I think
we're gonna have to I think we're going
to have to elect a new system we're
gonna say to people how badly do you
want to you know to actually take care
of this planet so that your kids can
have a decent world how badly do you
want to get
get free and never be fighting about
money again how badly do you want to get
out of worse sending are you know how do
you world at peace if you want to do
this then let's elect a system that will
enable that and so electing a new system
man that's right if we're not gonna do
it that way it's going to be a
revolution it's gonna come like try it
with Hong Kong had a million people and
then the next year they had two million
people out in the streets protesting and
you've seen that Hong Kong you know it's
coming we had more than a million people
protesting the war or the Iraq war in
the on the streets of London whenever it
was ten years ago fifteen years ago
whenever it was now my turn time goes by
but you know it'll make any difference
we still went to war in Iraq it made
absolutely no bloody difference that
three-quarters of the country was
against it they didn't give a shit there
was money to be made and there has been
made to President Bush and whatever and
so we went anyway just just coming back
to the other thing that I wanted to talk
to you about and sorry to keep coming
back to my own idea but what did you
think of what do you think of this sort
of none of the above kind of banner as a
starting point the reason I ask is let
me just finish the question the reason I
ask is that one of the things that has
struck me in the four or five years that
I've been involved in the zeitgeist
movement and the money free party and
activism in general is the fractious
nature of the activist community you
know what I mean that the one group
splinters off into two groups of
splinters up into four groups because
they each now develop their own
particular concerns and they forget that
actually we're all on the same team you
know what I mean and that and the the
the the uniting under one simple idea I
mean this is what this is what occupy
almost got right yeah they or they they
they almost got it they got everyone
other extinction rebellion you mentioned
earlier on as well you know they've got
one idea you know the government must do
something about climate change I mean I
don't I don't personally agree with
their agenda but that's one side they
have the strength of all united behind
one clear unambiguous this is what we
all want issue
this is what the RBE and activist
community in general has absolutely
failed to do I mean even Jacque fresco
and Peter Joseph managed to fall out
about something or other god knows what
it was you know you could make two more
people more closely aligned than them
right and yeah you know and I see this
happen again and again and again and
again and again I've been part of the
zeitgeist movement for four or five
years now new people can't they drift
into the movement and then they go off
and they join other movements where they
just drift away from it you know there's
a there's an inability to hang on to
people there's an inability to keep
people engaged there's an inability to
set people what they feel to be
meaningful tasks that they the step
towards you know the the final goal kind
of thing and we're badly organized
extinction rebellion did this extremely
well extinction rebellion had regular
meetings right where they would get
together in a in a classroom or a town
hall or a church all or someone's living
room or whatever and they would receive
training how to deal with the police
what happens when you get arrested you
know what kinds of things you should
wear what you know how to deal with your
rubbish you need to do when you go to
and when you need to go to the toilet
all of this kind of stuff that's going
to come up when you're out marching
being an activist and it gives people a
sense of ongoing continued meaningful
involvement you know what I mean and and
and yeah here's an RBE community have
dismal II failed to do that in my
opinion you know there's no cohesion
there's lots and lots of infighting
argumentation and there's no structure
to actually hang on to new recruits and
and and develop them in whatever way you
know what I mean yeah yeah I know
exactly what you mean and yeah I know I
know it's a problem and I don't exactly
know what the answer is yeah yeah I know
it's some people get frustrated because
the structure that we are up against is
so immense and it just looks like it's
gonna be impossible to to actually
change it around into a healthy
collaborative sustainable world
it just seems so impossible or not
that's why do you know you know getting
rid of via feedback Chopra
you know Deepak Chopra yeah I heard him
say once in an interview that the only
way to bring about meaningful change
would be to lace the water supply with
psilocybin or less that is how you do
about that special mushroom dinner yeah
you can't behave and think and see the
things in the same way afterwards can
you I mean unless you really dig
yourself a big denial hole you just
can't continue on the same way
afterwards yeah all right well people
are just too controlled by the system
and they're gonna have to yeah they're
gonna have to get a vision of what it
could be like they're gonna have to be
able to see it right that's all job is
to provide them with that vision that's
that's all job yeah I know Colin was
talking about you know trying to make a
movie and TV t Venus Project has been
talking about trying to make a movie as
a way to get it in front of the people
that people see what this could look
like and Peter Joseph's project he's
been working on forever here he's gonna
try to do that
yeah what's happening reading some
reflections have you had any news on
that do you know what's happening with
that I just I just know that he's taking
him he's sort of going one direction
with it and then kind of maybe thinking
not that might not quite working it a
little bit back and forth I don't know
if anybody's doing but it's so much
harder to put together a a movie project
as opposed to a documentary you know dr.
Harry fairly simple when you compared
compared it to trying to put together a
full-length feature film that you're
going to get people to come out and get
engaged with you really need a plot and
something to draw the draw people
yeah then you need to just have the
society as a backdrop sort of to the
story anyway that's where he was talking
about that or what Colin was talking
about it I was going I'm glad I'm not
writing that script because because it'd
be really hard I wrote a dozen
screenplays when I was about 10 years
when I was working it's writing
screenplays and so I know how to do it
and it's hard and I've often thought
about how how could you present it we're
getting a story to get people involved
and letting them see the society that
has changed into this healthy yeah I've
got a couple of sort of vague I did not
now we won't go into it now but maybe we
could discuss another time because I've
actually got a couple of ideas for
stories and I I I enjoy writing I've no
experience of writing screenplays but I
enjoy writing and I like to think I have
a reasonable facility with language we
can I know you've done your time and
everything but we could maybe at some
point in the future talk about maybe
collaboration because I do have a couple
of ideas for exactly that the context in
which to present that sort of contrast
between now and then not specific only a
vague outline I can I see something
vague our story with moving
transitioning into this system but you
know somebody that wants to try to hold
back this change from happening and have
some conflict there and then you know
just very vague idea again it's fairly
vague but I've got this notion of an
alien encounter kind of thing where
whatever I mean come up with other
storylines that go on between the
protagonists but that the underlying
thread is a sort of dialogue that goes
on between the earth hero and the alien
hero as to how things are in their
worlds right and then the contrast
between a genuinely civilized society
and us can easily be drawn right and
you know it can be too likable
characters coming from two different
worlds and and and you know and I think
that it could be done quite nicely I
think like that without a bit without it
being Joey so as I say there's only a
vague notion but I think it has some
potential as a structure to exactly that
show that content I mean Peter Joseph's
idea within two reflections is to do it
as a sort of it happened in the past
right telling the story about the
transition which has already happened at
some point in the past that was the idea
within two reflections wasn't it I think
even sure he never had you know it's
never really going into it too much like
three four years ago he made a trailer
for it all right that was the last I
heard he was supposed to come out early
in 2017 then it was delayed a lot autumn
to 17 and then I haven't heard anything
since so long similarly is called the
shift that they were trying to raise
funds I saw a couple of trailers for
that on YouTube and again it looks
excellent but again as far as I'm aware
it didn't actually amount to anything
right I remember that - I remember
seeing that trailer and I thought it
should be a good idea a filmmaker from
Finland or someone of the Norwegian
countries I think anyway well we'll have
to talk about that that might be a fun
project for me to take on after this one
I know I know from this year and a half
now I'm just going to be trying to
promote a new you know a new system that
people can envision and then I can try
to just be talking about on as many
platforms out there as I can and you
know presenting this vision so yes let's
finish where we started then and go back
to talking about your campaign what
platforms do you get access to that you
wouldn't otherwise have access to as a
presidential candidate any at all given
that you're a minority candidate or is
it up to you entirely to chisel out your
own media agencies I guess you know how
interesting I can be like I say I'm
gonna be on this one showing and that's
me
- with Korea Melwood who's a great guy
you know the longer jimmy doors are just
I mean they advocate for a you know
progressive left-wing politics but you
know try to explain it down that even we
get better people elected you know the
structure is not going to allow very
much change but if I can be a good guest
on there and in 15 or 20 minutes try to
get this mission across then maybe Jimmy
door was good and then there's 10 or 20
internet shows that have got big
audiences that I could get on and reach
a lot of people and so you know am I
gonna be a good guest will somebody see
me on there once we go that sounds that
you're seeing let's have him on our show
if I can start doing a bunch of shows
and reaching more and more people maybe
maybe I can get somewhere okay Jimmy
Kimmel those guys you know Bill Maher is
really uh he used to be the
anti-establishment guy but now he's
pretty much turned into the
establishment and okay you know he's all
for capitalism and he he only goes so
far and he's you know he's on mainstream
channels and they won't let him they
won't let him have somebody come on and
talk about getting rid of the
corporation's yeah which means getting
rid of them I mean Conan O'Brien I
remember he did an expose of the media
narrative thing right where they showed
like 50 different news channels reading
exactly the same like verbatim worker
newsroom man and making the point very
clearly that you can't you know that
this is all pre all your music
prepackaged right it's just distributed
and read out it's not investigated it's
not a check it's not verified you know
just handed yeah
but this isn't the system we're talking
about here would it's it's getting
really corporate control its dissolving
the corporation's which means they're
all out of a job now if they can see
that it's gonna be a better world for
them to like we talked about
they can never been a better life too
but still this structure of the
corporate media is not going to allow
somebody was as radical ideas as we have
to come on and talk today you're running
for president even though you are
legitimately a presidential candidate
have you I mean just in the interest of
balance right I mean you could make that
case right just in the interest of
balance I'm fuckin a residential
candidate you know I mean what your
voice really this is America man
yeah I'll be putting that argument out
there in the mostly here I'll be saying
that we'll see if I can convince yeah
all right but I will I will chop it down
into into some kind of coherent
45-minute ish kind of thing that'll be
good put the whole thing up straight
away I mean I'll cut out the bits when
we went for toilet breaks and shit like
that but yeah I will put the whole thing
up very shortly so if you want to take
any clips from her own used to you you
can do that straight away pretty much
okay if I really email you there's some
links to a couple videos you can just
put links on the on the messenger thing
right you can do that's mine and yeah I
think that's about it it may take me a
week or two to get around to finishing
the edit it takes a surprisingly long
time in the end because it's not as
simple as just chopping bits out you end
up moving things around because it flows
better that way whatever and so on so
doing Asian I did one with Erika Erika
Sunday yeah yeah yeah that way like 25
minutes and I cut it down to 18 minutes
it took it took a while to do you know
what
it wasn't that easy so yeah so I know no
hurry whenever you get around to I think
to be honest just journalistically not
that I'm claiming to be a journalist but
just journalistically I think it's right
to put the unedited version up as well
right so that any possible
misrepresentations can be clarified
straight away I don't know for me I
would just cut it down to what I think
is is the most interesting part of you
yeah people really just don't have that
you know 45 minutes it seems to be as
long as most people are gonna sit down
to watch something and so I you know I
don't need to see and then this there's
no any worry about anything being
misrepresented can't be aired right so
yeah okay great just whatever you want
to do makeup Eric you mean you I love
talking to the fellow are be heat
friends out there yeah likewise likewise
it makes you feel you're not entirely
alone in the world right that's right
yeah looking to others that actually did
actually get it anyway LCC its yeah yeah
I would really love to see many free
party France many free party Austria you
know just going down the country because
we have RBE supporters every you never
find a way to unite all of these money
free people with the Venus Project
people with the three charter people
with the with the zeitgeist movement
people with the United all of the we
need to find a way to get all of these
people onto a page that they can all
agree on you know what I mean whatever
which is why I like none of the above I
like the simplicity of none of the above
it seems to me a good starting point we
reject this and now let's have a serious
conversation about what we want to
replace it with you know what I mean no
I like it I really do the more I think
about it I've been thinking about this
for a year or so you know the more I
think about none of the above and it
started off as a really silly idea right
because it's Brewster's Millions right
richard pryor silly funny but the
morning
the more I think it's got real legs as a
revolutionary act you know what I mean
rather than people taking to the streets
with tear gas and guns and patterns and
throwing rocks at each other and so on
which is usually what it generates into
when people get really really really
fucked off with things right if instead
of their that protest that anger that
dissatisfaction could be channeled into
just know just know and I know
campaigning for a negative is is
generally speaking a terrible thing to
do I completely understand nation would
be campaigning for positive change and
not you know aunty this auntie but but
it is to me this is a positive act of
rejection in order to begin the
transition to the new thing with it
because you have to do that as you've
already said there's no way it happens
under this system and so you have to
stop its first before you learn and I
think none of the above is potentially
an effective way to do that it's
something that everyone in the RBA
community can get you because we all
think that this has to fucking go
right we all think man yeah so I think
it could be an effective uniting yeah if
it's really if it's really the lesser of
two evils which is pretty much for all
of our elections and people could do
that you know neither beadles neither
yeah all right sounds good to me
state it was a pleasure
same as you Eric I'll be in contact will
be talking I talk more about maybe
writing something together because I'm
really I'm really into there I mean
that's only the beginning right then you
got to find funding to actually fucking
thing but you know if you know I think
good enough people will fund it yeah no
I'll send you the link to this movie
that I wrote and shot TV movie yeah I've
noticed it on there I've been on that
channel is called twisted faith
actors were really good and the one girl
who played the lead in it she went on to
out to LA and started doing a plays and
commercials and couple TV things then
she went back to Broadway and she was a
lot of big Broadway shows and she was up
for Best Actress in a Musical for the
Tony Awards a couple years ago so really
talented people that I was lucky enough
to get in that you know anyway great
well you sold it to me i watch it that's
right very great talking to you take it
easy they